Guide to the Herbert Feigl Papers, 1916-1973 ASP.1997.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Herbert Feigl Papers
1916-1973
1930-1973
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Feigl, Herbert
ASP.1997.01
24 microfilm_reels
Herbert Feigl was born in 1902 in Reichenberg, Bohemia, and was one of the leading proponents of logical positivism and a member of the Vienna Circle. He also made significant contributions in the field of contemporary materialism and made extensive use of advances in physiological psychology. The papers comprise correspondence and manuscripts including exchanges with Bar-Hillel, Carnap, Einstein, Frank, Hempel, Hook, Neurath, Oppenheim, Reichenbach, Russell, and other 20th century thinkers. Included are also notes and lectures outlines as well as an extensive collection of his published and unpublished papers that discuss social issues and philosophical problems in psychology.
Biography
Herbert Feigl was born in 1902 in Reichenberg, Bohemia. He studied mathematics, physics, psychology, and philosophy at the Universities of Munich and Vienna. In 1927, he received his doctorate from the University of Vienna, for a dissertation on the foundations of probability and induction in the exact sciences.
From 1925 to 1930, Feigl was an important member of the Vienna Circle. It was then that he came into close association with Carnap, Frank, Schlick, Reichenbach, Waismann, Wittgenstein, and many other leading philosophers of the time. Feigl lectured in astronomy and in the philosophy of science at the Vienna People's Institute from 1927 to 1930. In 1929, his book, Theorie und Erfahrung in der Physik (Theory and Experience in Physics), won approval from Albert Einstein. The following year Feigl went to Harvard University on an International Rockefeller Fellowship to work on the logical foundations of physics.
In 1931, Feigl joined the Philosophy Department at the University of Iowa as a lecturer, and in 1941 he accepted an appointment as Professor of Philosophy at the University of Minnesota. In September 1953, the Minnesota Center for Philosophy of Science was established under a grant from the Louis W. and Maud Hill Family Foundation. Feigl was appointed director of the Center, a position he held until his death in 1989.
Feigl was one of the leading proponents of logical positivism. He also made significant contributions in the field of contemporary materialism. Unlike many others, he considered materialism a serious philosophical theory. In his work on the central-state theory of materialism, Feigl made extensive use of advances in physiological psychology.
Scope and Content Notes
An extensive part of the papers consists of correspondence and manuscript drafts. Feigl's correspondence includes exchanges with Bar-Hillel, Carnap, Einstein, Frank, Hempel, Hook, Neurath, Oppenheim, Reichenbach, Russell, and other 20th century thinkers. The correspondence not only provides valuable information on Feigl's views, but also serves as important documentation of others' philosophical development. The collection contains manuscripts of important articles by Born, Carnap, Oppenheim, Popper, Reichenbach, Stegmüller, and others. In addition, there are notes, lectures and lecture outlines. Feigl's notes cover various topics in the natural sciences, mathematics, and philosophy. Many of his published and unpublished lectures and papers deal with social issues and philosophical problems in psychology.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into six series:
Series I: Biographical Material
Series II: Academic and Professional Activities
Series III: Correspondence
Series IV: Writings by Feigl
Series V: Writings by Others
Series VI: Offprints by Others
Existence and Location of Originals
The original Feigl collection is housed at the University of Minnesota. Researchers should note that the University of Minnesota reserves all rights to the collection and must approve all requests to quote from or publish materials. The Archives of Scientific Philosophy at the University of Pittsburgh and the Philosophisches Archiv at the University of Konstanz, Germany, possess microfilms of the entire Feigl Collection available for use by researchers. This arrangement is made possible by a cooperative agreement between the University of Pittsburgh and the University of Konstanz, with the generous support fo the Minnesota Center for the Philosophy of Science.
Acquisition Information
Under a collaborative agreement, the University of Pittsburgh archivally processed the original Feigl Papers in 1990. The papers then returned to their home repository at the University of Minnesota Archives. In exchange, the University of Pittsburgh received a microfilm copy of the papers for deposit at Pitt's Archives of Scientific Philosophy.
Previous Citation
Herbert Feigl Papers, 1916-1973, ASP.1997.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Logical positivism; Correspondence; Personal papers; Science -- Philosophy; Philosophy; Mind and body; University of Minnesota. Department of Philosophy; Minnesota Center for Philosophy of Science; Institute for the Unity of Science; American Philosophical Society; Stegmüller, Wolfgang; Skinner, B. F. (Burrhus Frederic); Sellars, Wilfrid; Scriven, Michael; Russell, Bertrand; Rozeboom, William W. (William Warren); Reichenbach, Hans; Putnam, Hilary; Popper, Karl R. (Karl Raimund); Oppenheim, Paul; Grünbaum, Adolf; Frank, Philipp; Feyerabend, Paul; Everett, Millard S. (Millard Spencer); Einstein, Albert; Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970; Buck, Roger C.; Brodbeck, May; Bradley, Raymond; Born, Max; Feigl, Herbert -- Archives; Bar-Hillel, Yehoshua; Gunderson, Keith; Hanson, Norwood Russell; Hempel, Carl G. (Carl Gustav); Hook, Sidney; Koch, Sigmund; Maxwell, Grover; McDiarmid, E. W. (Errett Weir); McMullin, Ernan; Meehl, Paul E. (Paul Everett); Mehlberg, Henry; Nagel, Ernest; Neurath, Otto
- Biographical Material, 1921-1971; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains documents related to Feigl's personal life such as a biographical summary, chronology of his life and career, and a curriculum vitae. In addition, there is correspondence between himself and Hans Strauss and newspaper articles about Feigl reporting on his lectures. Other documents comprise his official birth and residency certificates, appointment letters, travel papers, awards received, and citizenship papers from 1921 to 1947.
  - Biographical Material, 1931-1959 (Reel 1, Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography of His Writings (Folder 2)
  - Feyerabend's Essay, 1966 (Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1923-1971 (Folder 4)
  - Official Documents, 1921-1947 (Folder 5)
  - Addresses and Business Cards (Folder 6)
  - Book Announcements, 1960-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Calendar, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Financial Records, 1939-1968 (Folder 9)
  - Notebook (Folder 10)
- Academic and Professional Activities, 1932-1971; II.
  The Academic and Professional Activities series is arranged into five subseries that reflect Feigl's participation in professional organizations and his overall professional activities. Included are a range of documents such as correspondence, programs, pamplets, financial records, meeting minutes, teaching materials, and newspaper articles. The correspondence in the subseries of the Institute for the Unity of Science relates activities and internal proceedings from 1939 to 1971. The subseries on Professional Organizations comprises programs, pamplets, and addresses from the the various professional organizations Feigl was associated with, including the American Association for Advancement of Science, the American Philosophical Association, and a pamplet concerning the Guggenheim Fellowships.The documents in the Teaching subseries range from outlines, course information, bibliographies, and student papers from 1941 to 1971. Finally, materials related to the University of Minnesota's Center for Philosophy of Science contain activity reports, meeting minutes for the department, project proposals, summaries of meetings, correspondence, and newspaper articles about the Center.
  - Institute for the Unity of Science, 1939-1971; 1.
    - Institute for the Unity of Science I., 1947-1966 (Folder 11)
    - Institute for the Unity of Science II., 1965-1967 (Folder 12)
    - Institute for the Unity of Science III., 1968-1971 (Folder 13)
    - Institute for the Unity of Science IV., 1966-1969 (Folder 14)
    - Institute for the Unity of Science V., 1939-1970 (Folder 15)
  - Professional Organizations, 1932-1970; 2.
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1943-1970 (Folder 16)
    - American Philosophical Association, 1932-1970 (Reel 2, Folder 17)
    - Institute of Twentieth Century Studies (Folder 18)
    - International Congress for the Philosophy of Science, 1935-1953 (Folder 19)
    - International Forum, 1961 (Folder 20)
    - International Union of History and Philosophy of Science, 1968 (Folder 21)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1947 (Folder 22)
    - Philosophy of Science Association, 1970 (Folder 23)
  - Teaching, 1941-1971; 3.
    - Bibliographies, 1953-1959 (Folder 24)
    - Course on Aristotle (Fr. McMullin), 1965-1966 (Folder 25)
    - Course on History and Philosophy of Physics (Dr. Feyerabend) (Folder 26)
    - Course on the Mind-Body Problem, 1953 (Folder 27)
    - Course on Philosophy of Language (Root), 1971 (Folder 28)
    - Course on the Philosophy of Psychology, 1955, 1958 (Folder 29)
    - Course on the Philosophy of Science, 1963 (Folder 30)
    - Notes for Freshman English Course Lecture, 1956-1959 (Folder 31)
    - Outlines, Notes, Etc., 1941-1970 (Folder 32)
    - Student Papers, 1952, 1968 (Folder 33)
    - Student Papers -- M.A. Thesis (Folder 34)
    - Student Papers (Fr. McMullin), 1965 (Folder 35)
  - University of Minnesota: Center for Philosophy of Science, 1951-1968; 4.
    - Activities Report, 1956-1957 (Folder 36)
    - Advisory Committee, 1953-1958 (Folder 37)
    - Applicants for Assistantships, 1960-1968 (Folder 38)
    - Hill Foundation, 1957, 1960 (Folder 39)
    - Materials Sent to the University of Pittsburgh, 1952-1960 (Folder 40)
    - Meetings, 1953-1955 (Folder 41)
    - Meetings, 1956-1966 (Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Folder 43)
    - News Service, 1953-1962 (Folder 44)
    - Notes on Setting up the Center, 1951-1965 (Reel 3, Folder 45)
    - Report on Summer Conference, 1957 (Folder 46)
  - University of Minnesota General, 1940-1971; 5.
    - General, 1940-1971 (Folder 47)
    - Department of Philosophy, 1964, 1968 (Folder 48)
- Correspondence, 1923-1973; III.
  The Correspondence series is divided into two subseries, reflecting both personal and professional exchanges with individuals, as well as correspondence with organizations and publishers. The second subseries also includes audiorecordings of lectures and a speech on philosophy of science dating from 1961 and 1968, as well as transcriptions of meetings from 1955 in Los Angeles and a 1954 meeting in Princeton.
  - Personal and Professional, 1923-1973; 1.
    - Abelson, Raziel, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Achinstein, Peter, 1966-1968 (Folder 2)
    - Allen, Reginald, 1961, 1965 (Folder 3)
    - Almont, Maxine M., 1965 (Folder 4)
    - Andersen, H. Carl, 1960 (Folder 5)
    - Anderson, Alan Ross, 1967 (Folder 6)
    - Anderson, Robert (Folder 7)
    - Apostel, L., 1964 (Folder 8)
    - Armleder, Paul J., 1965 (Folder 10)
    - Armacost, George H., 1960 (Folder 9)
    - Armstrong, David, 1967, 1969 (Folder 11)
    - Arner, Douglas G., 1967 (Folder 12)
    - Aronson, Jason, 1966 (Folder 13)
    - Artmann, Paul, 1950, 1952 (Folder 14)
    - Aschenbrenner, Karl, 1958 (Folder 15)
    - Aune, Bruce, 1960-1962 (Folder 16)
    - Axtelle, George, 1961 (Folder 17)
    - Ayers, Robert H., 1961 (Folder 18)
    - Babcock, C. M., 1949 (Folder 19)
    - Baier, Kurt, 1961, 1966 (Folder 20)
    - Bar-Hillel, Y., 1952-1970 (Folder 21)
    - Bartley, W. W., III, 1961-1967 (Folder 22)
    - Baumer, William H., 1967 (Folder 23)
    - Baumrin, Bernard H., 1962 (Folder 24)
    - Beard, Robert W., 1961 (Folder 25)
    - Beardsley, Monroe, 1961 (Folder 26)
    - Beck, Lewis W., 1961 (Folder 27)
    - Beer, Arthur, 1968-1971 (Folder 28)
    - Benson, Arthur J., 1954-1955 (Folder 29)
    - Bertocci, Peter A., 1969-1970 (Folder 30)
    - Beth, E. W., 1953 (Folder 31)
    - Bhawan, Bharati, 1969 (Folder 32)
    - Bischof, Norbert, 1966-1967 (Folder 33)
    - Bjornson, R. G. B., 1970-1971 (Folder 34)
    - Black, Max, 1945, 1961 (Folder 35)
    - Blackmore, John T., 1969 (Folder 36)
    - Blatnik, John A., 1960 (Folder 37)
    - Blau, Joseph L., 1950 (Folder 38)
    - Blegen, Theodore C., 1960 (Folder 39)
    - Blumberg, Albert E., 1959-1969 (Folder 40)
    - Bohnert, Herbert G., 1954-1955 (Folder 41)
    - Boring, Edwin G., 1934-1960 (Folder 42)
    - Bowen, Howard R., 1940 (Folder 43)
    - Bracken, Harry M., 1961, 1966 (Folder 44)
    - Bradley, Raymond D., 1966-1968 (Folder 45)
    - Bragg, Raymond B., 1939-1945 (Folder 46)
    - Braithwaite, R. B., 1967 (Folder 47)
    - Brandt, Richard B., 1954-1967 (Folder 48)
    - Bridgman, P. W., 1931 (Folder 49)
    - Brkic', Jouan, 1966 (Folder 50)
    - Brosin, Henry W., 1951 (Folder 51)
    - Bruiger, D., 1965 (Folder 52)
    - Brunswik, Egon, 1954-1955 (Folder 53)
    - Bub, Jeffrey, 1967 (Folder 54)
    - Buchta, J. W., 1945 (Folder 55)
    - Buchwald, Alexander M., 1959 (Folder 56)
    - Buck, G. E., 1955 (Folder 57)
    - Buck, Roger C., 1954-1966 (Folder 58)
    - Bunge, Mario, 1956-1970 (Folder 59)
    - Bures, Charles, 1965 (Folder 60)
    - Burhoe, Ralph W., 1954-1969 (Folder 61)
    - Burian, Richard M., 1967 (Folder 62)
    - Burham, Donald L., 1961 (Folder 63)
    - Burns, Cynthia, 1964 (Folder 64)
    - Bush, S. (Folder 65)
    - Campbell, Donald T., 1958-1966 (Folder 66)
    - Capek, M., 1971 (Folder 67)
    - Carleton, Robert H., 1966 (Folder 68)
    - Carnap, Rudolf, 1933-1970 (Folder 69)
    - Cassel, J. Frank, 1959 (Folder 70)
    - Cassirer, Eva, 1957 (Folder 71)
    - Castañeda, Héctor Neri, 1954-1956 (Folder 72)
    - Caws, Peter J., 1965-1967 (Folder 73)
    - Cerf, Walter, 1955 (Folder 74)
    - Chambers, Bette, 1965 (Folder 75)
    - Cheng, Chung-ying, 1971 (Folder 76)
    - Chisholm, Roderick M., 1960 (Folder 77)
    - Clendinnen, John, 1965-1966 (Folder 78)
    - Cobb, Stanley, 1960 (Folder 79)
    - Cohen, I. Bernard, 1961 (Folder 80)
    - Cohen, Robert S., 1953-1971 (Folder 81)
    - Collins, Joseph D., 1969 (Folder 82)
    - Colodny, Robert G., 1971 (Folder 83)
    - Conger, George P., 1954, 1963 (Folder 84)
    - Craig, Hamilton A., 1955 (Folder 85)
    - Crockett, Campbell, 1961 (Folder 86)
    - Crosson, Frederick J., 1965, 1967 (Folder 87)
    - Culbertson, James T., 1959 (Folder 88)
    - Curiel, Jose Luis, 1963 (Folder 89)
    - Cutler, Preston S., 1960 (Folder 90)
    - Dalen, Per, 1968 (Folder 91)
    - Damerell, V. R., 1967 (Folder 92)
    - Darzins, A. Luis, 1966 (Folder 93)
    - Davis, Ardie, 1964 (Folder 94)
    - Demos, Raphael, 1954 (Folder 95)
    - Dennes, William R., 1945-1946 (Folder 96)
    - Destouches, Jean-Louis, 1956-1957 (Folder 97)
    - Deterline, William A., 1959-1960 (Folder 98)
    - Dockx, S., 1965, 1971 (Folder 99)
    - Dodd, Stuart C., 1964 (Folder 100)
    - Dolphin, Vernon, 1960 (Folder 101)
    - Donagan, Alan, 1959, 1962 (Folder 102)
    - Dretske, Frederick I., 1964 (Folder 103)
    - Ducasse, C. J., 1945-1961 (Folder 104)
    - Dulit, Everett, 1961-1964 (Folder 105)
    - Dupuis, Adrian M., 1955 (Folder 106)
    - Durham, B. (Folder 107)
    - Dyanson, Diana, 1963 (Folder 108)
    - Easton, David, 1957 (Folder 109)
    - Easton, Loyd D., 1967 (Folder 110)
    - Echeverria, D. Luis, 1970 (Folder 111)
    - Economos, Judith, 1965-1972 (Folder 112)
    - Edman, Irwin, 1950 (Folder 113)
    - Edwards, Hans, 1966, 1970 (Folder 114)
    - Edwards, Paul, 1956-1970 (Folder 115)
    - Eilstein, Hélena, 1960, 1966 (Folder 116)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1929, 1943 (Folder 117)
    - Eitner, Lorenz, 1963 (Folder 118)
    - Ekstein, Rudolf, 1955, 1966 (Folder 119)
    - Elliott, R. Michael, 1940-1958 (Folder 120)
    - Ellis, Albert, 1954-1955 (Folder 121)
    - Ellis, Brian D., 1965-1966 (Folder 122)
    - Elsasser, Walter M., 1957 (Folder 123)
    - Elwyn, Mary, Sister, 1966 (Folder 124)
    - Estes, W. K., 1953 (Folder 125)
    - Everett, Millard S., 1931-1970 (Folder 126)
    - Fajans, Kasimir, 1960 (Folder 127)
    - Falk, John, 1953-1954 (Folder 128)
    - Fang, Joong, 1959 (Folder 129)
    - Farau, Alfred, 1960 (Folder 130)
    - Farber, Marvin, 1967 (Folder 131)
    - Fernley, George, 1967 (Folder 132)
    - Feyerabend, Paul, 1957-1968 (Folder 133)
    - Filerman, Gary, 1959 (Folder 134)
    - Filiasi-Carcano, P., 1954-1955 (Folder 135)
    - Firth, Roderick, 1958 (Folder 136)
    - Fleming, Donald, 1966-1967 (Folder 137)
    - Flew, Anthony, 1961 (Folder 138)
    - Flores, Nicholas Molina, 1964 (Folder 139)
    - Fodor, 1966 (Folder 140)
    - Forester, Leslie S., 1957 (Folder 141)
    - Frank, Phillip, 1951 (Folder 142)
    - Freeman, Eugene, 1971-72 (Folder 143)
    - Frenkel-Brunswik, Else, 1956 (Folder 144)
    - Freudenthal, H., 1967 (Folder 145)
    - Frey, Gerhard, 1959 (Folder 146)
    - Fries, Horace, 1949-1950 (Folder 147)
    - Frings, Manfred S., 1959 (Folder 148)
    - Fritz, Charles A. Jr., 1956 (Folder 149)
    - Fulcher, Gordon S., 1955 (Folder 150)
    - Fu-Sheng, Yin, 1953-1954 (Folder 151)
    - Gadsby, Dwight W., 1962 (Folder 152)
    - Garver, Newton, 1958, 1965 (Folder 153)
    - Gellhorn, E., 1961 (Folder 154)
    - Gieschen, Donald W., 1959-1961 (Folder 155)
    - Gilpatric, Chadbourne, 1954-1960 (Folder 156)
    - Gittler, Joseph B., 1954 (Folder 157)
    - Globus, Gordon G., 1971 (Folder 158)
    - Goe, George, 1965-1971 (Folder 159)
    - Goodman, Nelson, 1954-1966 (Folder 160)
    - Gordon, Otto J., 1968 (Folder 161)
    - Gorlow, Leon, 1961-1970 (Folder 162)
    - Götlind, Erik, 1957-1961 (Folder 163)
    - Gould, James A., 1964-1965 (Folder 164)
    - Gressley, Gene M., 1974 (Folder 165)
    - Groenewold, H. J., 1958, 1967 (Folder 166)
    - Gruen, William, 1954-1955 (Folder 167)
    - Gruender, David, 1962 (Folder 168)
    - Grünbaum, Adolf, 1953-1970 (Reel 4, Folder 169)
    - Grunberg, Emile, 1951-1961 (Folder 170)
    - Grunebaum, L. H., 1963 (Folder 171)
    - Gruner, Wayne R., 1967 (Folder 172)
    - Guillemin, Victor Jr., 1966 (Folder 173)
    - Gunderson, Gary R., 1965-1967 (Folder 174)
    - Gunderson, Keith, 1965-1967 (Folder 175)
    - Gutmann, James, 1955 (Folder 176)
    - Hackley, Helen L., 1964 (Folder 177)
    - Halberg, Franz, 1965 (Folder 178)
    - Hall, A. Rupert, 1961 (Folder 179)
    - Hall, Jay, 1958 (Folder 180)
    - Hallberg, Fred W., 1970 (Folder 181)
    - Halleck, Charles A., 1960 (Folder 182)
    - Hamann, Jon Ray, 1967 (Folder 183)
    - Hammond, Kenneth R., 1960 (Folder 184)
    - Handy, Rollo, 1965-1966 (Folder 185)
    - Hanson, Frank Blair, 1940 (Folder 186)
    - Hanson, Nancy K., 1970 (Folder 187)
    - Hanson, Norwood Russell, 1958-1966 (Folder 188)
    - Hartshorne, Charles, 1961, 1967 (Folder 189)
    - Harwood, E. C., 1960 (Folder 190)
    - Hauer, Herbert J., 1957 (Folder 191)
    - Hausman, Carl R., 1965-1966 (Folder 192)
    - Havas, Peter, 1951 (Folder 193)
    - Hawton, Hector, 1964 (Folder 194)
    - Hay, William, 1952 (Folder 195)
    - Hayek, F. A., 1954, 1960 (Folder 196)
    - Hebb, Donald O., 1954 (Folder 197)
    - Heckman, A. A., 1952-1967 (Folder 198)
    - Heidelberger, Herbert, 1961, 1964 (Folder 199)
    - Heilman, Robert B., 1959 (Folder 200)
    - Heller, Keith, 1957 (Folder 201)
    - Hempel, Carl G., 1934-1970 (Folder 202)
    - Henle, Mary, 1967 (Folder 203)
    - Herbst, Peter, 1963 (Folder 204)
    - Hesse, Mary, 1967 (Folder 205)
    - Hilgard, Ernest R., 1949 (Folder 206)
    - Hill, Edward L., 1957 (Folder 207)
    - Hine, Frederick R., 1960 (Folder 208)
    - Hines, Howard H., 1967 (Folder 209)
    - Hintikka, Jaakko, 1969-1970 (Folder 210)
    - Hirsch, Jerry, 1960 (Folder 211)
    - Hochkeppel, Willy, 1966 (Folder 212)
    - Hodermarsky, Dan, 1955 (Folder 213)
    - Holt, Allen, 1962 (Folder 214)
    - Holton, Gerald, 1960 (Folder 215)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1949-1968 (Folder 216)
    - Hooker, C. A., 1965-1966 (Folder 217)
    - Hospers, John, 1957-1967 (Folder 218)
    - Houck, Dewey (Folder 219)
    - Huckabee, Weyman C., 1959 (Folder 220)
    - Hudson, Donald E., 1953 (Folder 221)
    - Huston, J. P., 1967 (Folder 222)
    - Ingarden, Roman, 1959 (Folder 223)
    - Ingle, Dwight J., 1960-1961 (Folder 224)
    - Jackson, Arthur M., 1965 (Folder 225)
    - Jackson, Arthur M. (Folder 226)
    - James, Marie, Sister, 1950 (Folder 227)
    - Jammer, Max, 1968, 1970 (Folder 228)
    - Jarvie, I. C., 1965 (Folder 229)
    - Jeffreys, Harold (Folder 230)
    - Johnson, Elisabeth, 1956 (Folder 231)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1959-1960 (Folder 232)
    - Joyce, Robert E., 1966 (Folder 233)
    - Judd, Walter H., 1960 (Folder 234)
    - Kain, Theodore, 1945 (Reel 4, Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Kaiser, D. Nolan, 1965-1967 (Folder 2)
    - Kalish, Donald, 1955 (Folder 3)
    - Kaltenbrunner, Gerd-Klaus, 1970 (Folder 4)
    - Kamitz, Reinhard, 1962 (Folder 5)
    - Kaplan, Abraham, 1953-1954 (Folder 6)
    - Kaplan, David, 1959, 1967 (Folder 7)
    - Kask, Uno, 1953 (Folder 8)
    - Katkovsky, Walter, 1958-1971 (Folder 9)
    - Kaufmann, Felix, 1945 (Folder 10)
    - Kaufmann, Walter A., 1966 (Folder 11)
    - Kay, George F., 1931, 1940 (Folder 12)
    - Kekes, John, 1965-1967 (Folder 13)
    - Kellner, G. W., 1930 (Folder 14)
    - Kemeny, John G., 1953 (Folder 15)
    - Kendler, Howard H., 1954 (Folder 16)
    - Kent, William P., 1956 (Folder 17)
    - Keyworth, Donald R., 1953 (Folder 18)
    - Kiewiet, Cornelis W. de. (Folder 19)
    - Kilpatrick, William H., 1950 (Folder 20)
    - Kirk, John R., 1955 (Folder 21)
    - Kitchner, Richard F., 1967, 1973 (Folder 22)
    - Klausner, Neal W. (Folder 23)
    - Klein, Howard A., 1959 (Folder 24)
    - Klemke, E. D., 1959-1961 (Folder 25)
    - Klineberg, Otto, 1964 (Folder 26)
    - Koch, Sigmund, 1953-1966 (Folder 27)
    - Koenig, F. O., 1943 (Folder 28)
    - Köhler, Wolfgang, 1957, 1959 (Folder 29)
    - Konvitz, Milton R., 1961-1972 (Folder 30)
    - Kotzin, Rhoda H., 1967 (Folder 31)
    - Kraft, Victor, 1928-1959 (Folder 32)
    - Kruseman, W. M., 1954 (Folder 33)
    - Lackner, Henry, 1961, 1968 (Folder 34)
    - Landé, Alfred, 1952-1965 (Folder 35)
    - Langer, George P., 1939 (Folder 36)
    - Langfeld, Herbert S., 1945 (Folder 37)
    - Laudan, Laurens, 1971 (Folder 38)
    - Lauerman, Fred J., 1966 (Folder 39)
    - Lauson, Warren A., 1965 (Folder 40)
    - Lauter, Herman Alfred, 1957 (Folder 41)
    - Leake, Chauncey D., 1959 (Folder 42)
    - Lean, Martin E., 1956 (Folder 43)
    - Lebrun, Harvey, 1966 (Folder 44)
    - Leeper, Robert, 1939 (Folder 45)
    - Lehrer, Keith, 1960-1965 (Folder 46)
    - Leinfellner, Werner, 1968 (Folder 47)
    - Lenzen, Victor F., 1950 (Folder 48)
    - Lepley, Ray, 1953-1954 (Folder 49)
    - Leven, Rals A., 1954 (Folder 50)
    - Levi, Albert W., 1964 (Folder 51)
    - Levi, Isaac, 1955-1962 (Folder 52)
    - Lewis, Clarence I., 1931-1933 (Folder 53)
    - Leys, Wayne, 1966 (Folder 54)
    - Lieb, Irwin C., 1959 (Folder 55)
    - Lindzey, Gardner, 1953-1954 (Folder 56)
    - Lippincot, Benjamin, 1964 (Folder 57)
    - Loewenstein, Rudolf M., 1954 (Folder 58)
    - Loftsgordon, Donald, 1960 (Folder 59)
    - Lowenstein, Otto, 1957 (Folder 60)
    - Luce, David Randall, 1959, 1965 (Folder 61)
    - Luckenbach, Sidney A., 1965-1970 (Folder 62)
    - Ludwig, Jack, 1961 (Folder 63)
    - Lukermann, Fred E., 1966 (Folder 64)
    - McCarroll, Tolbert H., 1963-1967 (Folder 65)
    - McCarthy, Eugene J., 1960 (Folder 66)